<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive  on Sam Norbury</title>
    <link>http://zy.io/categories/archive-/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive  on Sam Norbury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 13:59:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://zy.io/categories/archive-/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 - Sweden</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-29-day-6-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 13:59:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-29-day-6-sweden/</guid>
      <description>Second of the batch updates, and hopefully the last as I should be nearing civilisation and signal again tomorrow.
The fifth day took us down from Tjaktra on the path to a hut called Salka. I stayed strong with my snowshoes, fairly attached now. Jon has spurned them, I think he&#39;s suspicious of them. Snow shoes are all well and good on the flat and when you&#39;re going uphill, but as we dropped 300m+ that day, I found that they&#39;re not so useful going downhill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 - Sweden - The story so far</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-29-day-4-sweden-the-story-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 13:59:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-29-day-4-sweden-the-story-so-far/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve so far come across absolutely nothing in the way of signal, as was to be expected. Most days I&#39;m finishing up far too tired to sit down and ramble on about my day, so here&#39;s a batch update.
The first day was pretty relaxed. Cold, but only just below zero. We sauntered through forests, along rivers and walked across a frozen lake for 3km. Our hut for the evening was Abiskojaure (all the Swedish words are probably misspelt and are definitely missing various accents) 16km away from Abisko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweden - Interlude - Predictions</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-interlude-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 20:47:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-interlude-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Probably going to be without Internet til we reach somewhere near the end now, so rather than make up 7 days of Swedish adventure and set them to auto post, I&#39;ll just make a series of predictions. Predictions that I either believe will come true, want to come true, or just things that I think are funny.
it&#39;s going to be damn cold this is the last bit of luxury I&#39;ll see for a while I&#39;ll run out of books in about three days time and wish I bought more whilst I still had Internet  the snowshoes will be a terrible idea Jon will be eaten by a grue Jon will be as laid back about this as he is everything else I&#39;ll have trouble explaining to the local police what a grue is everything will have dairy in it, I just won&#39;t know what it&#39;s called all my pictures will be massively over exposed due to all the snow we&#39;ll discover that renting a dog sled is cheaper than renting snow shoes I&#39;ll be forced to try some form of pickled fish Jon will find some salt liquorice and try and make me eat some I&#39;ll grow a glorious beard due to 6 days not shaving we&#39;ll manage to not see the northern lights, despite us bring in the best place in the world to do so I&#39;ll make another pointless list I&#39;ll come back to this when I find some more internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweden - Day 1 - Abisko</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-day-1-abisko/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 20:46:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-day-1-abisko/</guid>
      <description>Our starting point has really been quite surprising. You&#39;d think a mountain station well within the arctic circle would be a bit sparse, but the reality is far from it. As you may have guessed, I have electricity and internet. We have a room to ourselves, heating, hot and cold water, the extravagance doesn&#39;t really stop. They&#39;re also serving restaurant quality food, which is a bit weird. Lunch was mussels and a variety of salads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweden - Day 1</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 13:20:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2014-03-23-sweden-day-1/</guid>
      <description>So I&#39;m on a train. Have been for 14 hours and there&#39;s still 4 to go. 18 hours is probably close to my annual quota for public transport, so it&#39;s good to get it out of the way in one chunk. Except I still have to head back.
We&#39;re (Jon and myself) on the way to Abisko, a place so far north it&#39;s practically Norway. The plan is then to saunter on down through Sweden, heading for a mountain to climb and a hut with the promise of hot water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspbmc/xbmc Subsonic plugin with video</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-08-27-raspbmcxbmc-subsonic-plugin-with-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 21:31:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-08-27-raspbmcxbmc-subsonic-plugin-with-video/</guid>
      <description>Rough, I&#39;ll amend this later.
I know it&#39;s hackish and the seds are very nasty, but it seems to work so far. Path of least resistance and all that.
Your mileage may vary
Need to be running full version of subsonic, or supersonic fork.
ssh in as pi user.
cd ~/.xbmc/addons
wget https://dl.dropbox.com/u/86110007/Subsonic%20for%20XBMC%20-%20Frodo.zip
unzip Subsonic\ for\ XBMC\ -\ Frodo.zip
find plugin.audio.subsonic/ -type f -exec sed -i &#39;s/Addon.log/xbmc.log/g&#39; {} \;
cp -rp plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why?</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2012-07-02-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 02:33:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2012-07-02-why/</guid>
      <description>Not really got any content for here at the moment, but seeing as you&#39;re here, have some information.
This whole server is a mishmash of technologies at the moment.
This blog comes in through varnish, to an nginx backend with php-fpm and just standard MySQL.
Others on here go to an apache/passenger backend, with Sinatra running some ruby junk for me and others are just straight up LAMP.
It&#39;s all likely to change of course, it&#39;s very much a dev box with this as a bit of a public scratchpad for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>