<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive on Sam Norbury</title>
    <link>http://zy.io/categories/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive on Sam Norbury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:31:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://zy.io/categories/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 14 - Rice wine strikes back</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-04-02-svn-day-14-rice-wine-strikes-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:31:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-04-02-svn-day-14-rice-wine-strikes-back/</guid>
      <description>Oh god, rice related beverages. The Chang was alright, but it was warm, contained about a tablespoon of cooked rice on top and had a thick layer of oil/butter on it. Our guide also got all militant and demanded we chug glass after glass of it. Then the Rakshi came out. He had us do this in shots, but it was still served by the half-mug. We soon discovered that the little lodge had a 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 13 - Sherpas</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-04-01-svn-day-13-sherpas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:39:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-04-01-svn-day-13-sherpas/</guid>
      <description>Today it rained for the first time on the trek. This was novel for about 5 minutes before I remembered I live in Manchester and am therefore fairly familiar with water falling from the sky.
As such, there wasn&#39;t much to report today during our walk from Kenguima to Monjo. We officially checked out of the national park but the rest of the day was spent trudging along in rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 12 - Ascent, again</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-12-ascent-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 03:15:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-12-ascent-again/</guid>
      <description>Today we&#39;ve been continuing our descent, moving on from Pheriche to Kenguima. Even though we dropped over 1000 metres we encountered quite a few &#39;Nepali flat&#39; sections whilst we traversed the various valleys along the way. Due to the fast approaching summiting season there&#39;s a constant stream of supplies heading up to base camp. This was fine whilst we were also walking to base camp, but now we&#39;ve turned around we&#39;re battling constantly against wave upon wave of yaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 11 part two - Descent</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-11-part-two-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 03:08:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-11-part-two-descent/</guid>
      <description>So the walk back to Lukla begins. As we&#39;re heading back from our highest point, you&#39;d think it would be all downhill, but once again we spent most of today climbing. Nepalese geography is weird.
Staying at Pheriche tonight, which is the only different village on the walk back down. The rest of the route is going to be identical from here on in. Feels a bit strange to be on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 11 part one - Summit</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-11-part-one-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 01:52:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-31-svn-day-11-part-one-summit/</guid>
      <description>Had to wake up horrendously early today for our 5am start to ascend Kala Patthar. It was a 3 hour round trip in total, including the usual photo taking at the summit.
Managed to make pretty good time, successfully back in time for breakfast. Not bad to say it was a 400 metre ascent to our highest point of the trip.
Now to start the journey back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 10 - Base camp</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-23-svn-day-10-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 04:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-23-svn-day-10-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Today was the day that our guide had been touting as our longest and most difficult day. With reason I guess, as its finally the day we reach base camp! As is to be expected, it&#39;s actually quite cold now, so I&#39;ve had to add a fleece and light waterproof to my usual t-shirt themed get up. Not sure what it is about this altitude, but I seem to be warm all the time now whilst everyone else is complaining about being freezing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Back in Kathmandu!</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-23-interlude-back-in-kathmandu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 04:21:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-23-interlude-back-in-kathmandu/</guid>
      <description>Still writing my backlog of posts up, but until then, let the caffeination commence!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 9 - The cold approaches</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-9-the-cold-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:27:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-9-the-cold-approaches/</guid>
      <description>Today was a fairly landmark day in that the majority of my time wasn&#39;t spent in a t-shirt. The wooly hat also made an appearance. I suppose I shouldn&#39;t really be surprised as we also broke 5000 metres today. Still not feeling much effect from the altitude beyond an increase in hunger and everyone else is wrapping up much warmer than me. Think there may be something wrong with me, some of the group is beginning to wonder if I&#39;m part Sherpa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 8 - Chhukhung</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-8-chhukhung/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:27:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-8-chhukhung/</guid>
      <description>Our stop at Dingboche is another acclimatisation day. They seemed to have stopped calling them rest days now, after realising that a haul up to 4800 metres isn&#39;t most people&#39;s idea of a rest.
Today was spent walking to Chhukhung, which was our highest (and also coldest) point sp far. Giving us some excellent views of a big chunk of the Himalayas.
Whilst a few members of the group are now really feeling the effects of AMS, two more have gone the opposite way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 7 - Yaks</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-7-yaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:24:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-22-svn-day-7-yaks/</guid>
      <description>We left our bleak, stone cold location at Tengboche this morning to head over to Dingboche. This involved heading down a big hill covered in ice. Normally this would be treacherous enough, but t make it more so we were surrounded by yaks. Due to their clumsiness, the best idea when yaks are passing is to scramble off the road to avoid being knocked over. The aforementioned ice made this much more fun, as the yaks aren&#39;t too big fans of heading down icy slopes either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 6 - AMS</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-21-svn-day-6-ams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 05:35:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-21-svn-day-6-ams/</guid>
      <description>AMS stands for acute mountain sickness, common name of altitude sickness. We reached 3850 metres today, and it seems like it&#39;s hit a few of our group quite hard. We had to leave one guy behind this morning, he was already too bad at Namche, but he can hopefully catch up with us on our next rest day. After our climb today, we&#39;ve been sat around after some food and the rest of the group look to be in various states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 5 - Rest</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-5-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 12:34:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-5-rest/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much got a lie in today, didn&#39;t get up until half six. Not so bad though, we all seem to slope off to bed about nine. Still don&#39;t seem to have got any altitude sickness effects, feeling cautiously optimistic. Who knows though, could spend the next four days throwing up. Probably best off I don&#39;t though.
So today was our hilly rest day. Our guide started the day by pointing up the nearest mountain and saying we were walking along that &#39;Nepali flat&#39; today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 4 - Ascent</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-4-ascent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 12:34:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-4-ascent/</guid>
      <description>It turns out yesterday ended with us at a lower altitude than we started at, so today was the start of our slog up the mountains. We gained about 900 vertical metres over the course of a 7+ hour hike up to Namche, so it was really quite steep in parts. As with yesterday, it&#39;s really quite warm whilst the sun is out, but the temperature drops to single figures as soon as it gets a bit dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvN - Day 3 - The hike begins</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-3-the-hike-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 12:33:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-13-svn-day-3-the-hike-begins/</guid>
      <description>Today was the true start of our trek, complete with walking, yaks and Sherpas. Before all this could happen though, we had to be acquainted with another terrifying form of Nepalese transportation, local flights.
A quick flight over the mountains in a small two prop plane may sound quite nice and idyllic, and it is for the most of it, it&#39;s just that the flight ends with you landing on a steep incline and having to do a handbrake turn (or whatever it is that planes do) to avoid hitting the wall/mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam vs Nepal - Day 2 - Kathmandu</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-10-sam-vs-nepal-day-2-kathmandu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 09:44:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-10-sam-vs-nepal-day-2-kathmandu/</guid>
      <description>And I thought the driving situation in Italy was bad...
We landed in Kathmandu rather successfully, which we followed up with what we thought would be a fairly average taxi ride from the airport. Turns out today is some major gathering at a Hindu temple between Kathmandu and the airport, with over 100,000 people in attendance. We managed to time the taxi ride perfectly with the end of this, so what followed was some sort of hellish slalom along a dirt road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam vs Nepal - Day 1 - the begin-ening</title>
      <link>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-09-sam-vs-nepal-day-1-the-begin-ening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zy.io/blog/2013-03-09-sam-vs-nepal-day-1-the-begin-ening/</guid>
      <description>Starting off the whole Sam vs Nepal thing with a lie I&#39;m afraid, I&#39;m not even in Nepal, currently sat in an airport in Doha.
The only thing I knew about Doha in advance was that the travel agency we&#39;re with recently voted it &#39;the most boring airport in the world&#39;. Excellent.
After a token walk around the duty free to pointlessly comment on the price of whisky I&#39;ll never drink we&#39;ve taken up residence in some uncomfortable chairs and prepared to abuse the free wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>